frugalandfunmom.com 2019-03-30

# Privacy Policy - Fun Learning Life

##### **Privacy Policy Updated 5/23/2018**

Fun Learning Life takes your privacy seriously. Because of this, the site has put measures into place to protect it, as well as provided information for you to take additional steps to limit what information is shared on the internet. This is a personal blog written and edited by me, that is intended for entertainment purposes only. This site does not sell personal information. 

I do not sell products at this site and any items or services linked are sold by independent vendors, and users should refer to those companies privacy policy’s when providing personal information. I do not take credit card information, phone numbers, or physical addresses through this website. See additional information about how products and services are displayed on this site by visiting [Site Disclosure.](https://funlearninglife.com/site-disclosure/ "Site Disclosure.")

##### COMMENTS:

By leaving comments on the site you are allowing that text to be public.  IP addresses are automatically collected and metadata is stored on comments indefinitely as a way to be checked through an automated spam detection service as well as a way to recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue. 

However, email addresses and IP addresses are not displayed publicly unless it is left in the actual comment by the individual commenting. An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service (Comment Profile created for WordPress) to see if you are using it  The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: [automattic.com/privacy](https://automattic.com/privacy/ "automattic.com/privacy"). After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

##### GIVEAWAYS:

In regards to giveaways, since this is my method of contact for winners and by leaving a comment with your email address you are agreeing to those terms. Fun Learning Life currently uses the 3rd party [rafflecopter.com](https://www.rafflecopter.com/ "rafflecopter.com") to administer giveaways and please refer to their privacy policy on how they store your information. 

Fun Learning Life does not share email addresses with 3rd parties unless specifically expressed in a specific promotion or giveaway. See the complete Giveaway Policy here: [Site Disclosure.](https://funlearninglife.com/site-disclosure/ "Site Disclosure.") This privacy policy does not apply to information collected such as names, email addresses, physical addresses, and phone numbers to fulfill giveaway prizes with a 3rd party.

##### NEWSLETTER:

Email addresses and names are also collected if you sign up for the site newsletter. This is managed by Google Feedburner a 3rd party. Users should refer to their privacy policy [Google Privacy and Terms](https://policies.google.com/ "Google Privacy and Terms") for additional information. 

If you would like to unsubscribe from the newsletter contact the site directly at [athomemoma2@gmail.com](https://funlearninglife.com/privacy-policy/athomemoma2@gmail.com "athomemoma2@gmail.com") or unsubscribe through the link provided in the newsletter.

##### DATA COLLECTION, WHAT RIGHTS YOU HAVE OVER YOUR DATA, AND DATA RENTENTION:  ****

This site uses 3rd parties to collect data for internal use, to measure demographics anonymously for advertisers, and to enhance the user’s experience. This is through products including Google Analytics as well as Google Adsense. The site also uses Statcounter to track daily traffic with truncated IP Addresses. This method of gathering information is often times also referred to as  **COOKIES**. 

You can visit this website anonymously from Google Analytics by adding the [Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout "Opt-out Browser Add-on") and you can take control of your ad experience at this site by visiting [Google Ad Settings](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated "Google Ad Settings"). To learn ways on how you can alter your ad experience, visit [youradchoices.com.](http://youradchoices.com/ "youradchoices.com.") For more details check out Google’s Privacy policy on how you can control the information shared in both Google Analytics and Google Adsense visit [Google Privacy and Terms](https://policies.google.com/ "Google Privacy and Terms"). To see Statcounter’s Privacy Policy visit [statcounter.com/about/legal](http://statcounter.com/about/legal/ "statcounter.com/about/legal")

Data collected at this site via comments is stored indefinitely. If you have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us.  As for Google Analytics, data is stored up to 14 months, as for Statcounter it is stored for 9 hours. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.  For details please feel free to email the site administrator at [athomemoma2@gmail.com](https://funlearninglife.com/privacy-policy/athomemoma2@gmail.com "athomemoma2@gmail.com"). 

##### EMBEDDED CONTENT FROM OTHER WEBSITES:

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

##### SITE ADMINISTRATION: 

Fun Learning Life does use third parties to administer the functions of the site through plugins as well as a website provider [bluehost.com](http://bluehost.com/ "bluehost.com"), and have put security measures into place to help protect these features. For a complete list of plugins used at this site, please feel free to email the site administrator at [athomemoma2@gmail.com](https://funlearninglife.com/privacy-policy/athomemoma2@gmail.com "athomemoma2@gmail.com").

I believe in transparency and if at any time I am made aware of a security breach that effects the limited personal information stored, I will post a notice at the site. Any updates to the privacy policy will be notated by the date on this page as well. 

##### USER AGREEMENT:

By using this site you agree to this privacy policy.

For any questions about this site’s Privacy Policy, please feel free to email the site administrator at [athomemoma2@gmail.com](https://funlearninglife.com/privacy-policy/athomemoma2@gmail.com "athomemoma2@gmail.com").
